

Abhijeet Sane

Software Developer / Technology Architect

Software developer with 19+ years of experience in designing, implementing and maintaining highly scalable distributed systems. Have good knowledge of Unix/Linux and multiple programming languages. Have good communication skills and capacity to work as team lead or in individual contributor roles.

abhijeet.sane@gmail.com

in abhijeetsane

A Pune, India

+91 9359373300

Skills

Scripting Languages Python, Shell Scripting, JavaScript/NodeJS, Perl, LETEX

Programming Languages C, C++

Operating Systems Linux,FreeBSD, DOS, Windows Virtualization VMware AppDirector, Citrix Xen

Frameworks Hapi

Cloud Technologies Amazon EC2

Database MySQL ,PostgreSQL, RethinkDB

Caching Redis

Gui QT Toolkit, Python/Tk

Tools GIT, CVS

APM Splunk, AppDynamics

Others Open Source, Software Reliability Engineering, High performance architectures, Estimation,

System integration, REST API, Performance Engineering

June 2021 - Current Date Pune ,MH , India Architect Technology, BlueConch Technologies

LANGUAGES / TECHNOLOGIES

JAVA , JAVASCRIPT , C/C++ , MYSQL,
REST WEBSERVICES

- ▶ Lead the transition of Rand McNally "Connected Vehical" product to BlueConch from 3rd party vendor.
- □ Understood the architecture of the product and acquired detailed technical understanding of the various subcomponents . Trained the BlueConch team to take over the product develoment and services of the product.
- ▷ Proposed new high-performance architecture to resolve current performance issues. The proposed stack consists of NodeJS ,TimeSeries databases , MQ and bespoke reporting services to be developed using a cloud agnostic approach.
- ▶ Lead the "Software Discovery team" for the **Deluxe** "Remote Deposit Capture" product. Analysed the current system architecture and created detailed technical analysis documentation. Proposed a new solution for the technology revamp inorder to remove the obsolete ActiveX components and move the solution to use modern WebUI using ReactJS. Worked on the time / resource utilization estimations.
- ▶ Leading the Data Analytics Focus group in BlueConch . Taking part in various customer technical analysis and RFP responses.

Abhijeet Sane 1/5

Work Experience

Sep 2020 - Current Date Pune ,MH , India

Principle Software Engineer, SevOne - Jeavio India Pvt Ltd

Languages / **Technologies** C++,C,MySQL,PHP,Git

- ▷ Resolving client esclations , performing root cause analysis and software performance issues.
- ▶ Platform related fixes and working on vulnerability resolution.

March 2020 - Sept 2020 Pune ,MH , India

Technology Architect, NNIP / Altis - Cognizant Technology Solutions

Languages / Technologies Python, PostGreSOL, Pandas

Python, PostGreSQL , Pandas , LaTex , Git

- ▷ Worked as part of the Switzerland/Netherland based Altis-NNIP asset management product team
- ▷ Developed POCs for various problem statements.
- ▷ Technology ownership and improvement planning. Feature development and bug fixing along with BAU activity executions.
- Documented the process flow, data flow and data interactions
- \triangleright Participated in knowledge transition . Application ownership, stake holder communication and problem solving.

Nov 2019 - March 2020 Pune ,MH , India

Technology Architect, KPMG - Cognizant Technology Solutions

APM APPLICATIONS

SPLUNK, APPDYNAMICS, SOLARWINDS, RESILIENCY, RELIABILITY, FAULT VULNERABILITY ASSESSMENT

- Conducted performance analysis for multiple critical KPMG applications. Analysed application health, reliability, resiliency and capacity utilization.
- ▷ Performed fault vulnerability assessment and provided recommendations for improvements.
- Developed multiple dashboards in Splunk and AppDyamics to help KPMG application owners in end to end application monitoring.

Aug 2018 - Nov 2019 Pune ,MH , India

Technology Architect, Kohls - Cognizant Technology Solutions

Languages / **Technologies** Python,R,InfluxDB , Redis

- ▷ Architect for implementing the Cognizant SmartAPM solution for Kohls US.
- Designed and developed a python based metric collector to collect KPI data from Kohls Splunk and push the KPI data to Influx DB in SmartAPM consumable form. Parallelized the metric collector to query multiple metrics at the same time and reduced the time to query.
- Developed the Bot Execution load balanced queuing and executer.
- > Automated the data loaders and AI bots batch execution scheduling.
- ▷ Integrated the SmartAPM notification engine with ServiceNow.
- ▷ Developed proof of concept SmartAPM Dashboard using Flask micro webframework and Redis for data caching.

Abhijeet Sane 2/5

Nov 2017 - 15 July 2018 Newark , DE , USA Project Manager / Software Developer, JPMC - Cognizant Technology Solutions

LANGUAGES / TECHNOLOGIES

PYTHON, PANDAS, VBSCRIPT, ENAML

- ▶ Work involves analyzing multiple user automated excel tools and automating those in Capital Desktop using Python programming language.
- $\,\rhd\,$ Fixing bugs in old user tools using VB script and ad hoc assignments.

Feb 2017 - Sep 2017 Chandler, AZ, USA Software Developer, Cognizant Technology Solutions

LANGUAGES / TECHNOLOGIES

Perl , Python , C/C++ ,QT , Linux ,Javascript

- $\,\rhd\,$ Fixing bugs in Perl , Python report generators and log analyzers

May 2016 - Feb 2017 Atlanta , GA , USA Technical Architect, Cognizant Technology Solutions

Languages / Technologies

 $\label{eq:lot_state} \begin{aligned} &\text{IoT}\,, \text{Linux}\,, \text{NodeJS}, \text{Edge Computing}\,, \text{Analytics} \end{aligned}$

- ▶ Worked on Internet of Things and Edge Computing architecture and proof of concept development.
- ▶ Worked as part of the architect team for Associated Press (one of the worlds largest news gathering organizations).

March 31 2015 - May 2016 Atlanta , GA , USA Onsite Lead (CNN-Turner)- Coordinator, Cognizant Global Technnology Office

Languages / Technologies

NodeJS , Perl , Python , Redis/Linux

- ▶ Worked in CNN Turner broadcasting systems as onsite tech lead for the "Editorial Events" team . Worked on bug fixes and feature development for Turner CNN.com website.
- ⊳ REST web services development and maintenance using NodeJS.Legacy data migration scripting using Perl and python.
- ightharpoonup Coordinating with on-site and offshore teams . Resolving teams technical issues. Proposing and getting solutions based on MEAN stack implemented.

Sep 2011 - March 31 2015 Pune , India Technology Specialist, Cognizant Technology Solutions

Languages / Technologies

NodeJS, Python, Perl, Redis

- Developed WalBox cloud storage application that allows users to store files on Eucalyptus Walrus block storage or Amazon S3 using Python.Developed the Windows user interface using Python/Tk library for the same product
- ▶ Working on developing the RESTful web services for Cognizant Social Tango using Node.JS and RethinkDB.Developed engine to store and generate the Activity Streams 2.0 compliant streams using nodejs and RethinkDB. Engine pre-created the activity stream instead of generating them on user demand.

Abhijeet Sane 3/5

Oct 2009 - Aug 2011 Pune . India Staff Product Developer, BMC Software

Languages/Technologies C/C++,Python,Perl

- ▶ Worked in the BMC Performance Assurance product line mainly working on the data metric collection module.
- Developed support for the Citrix Xen platform metric collector and multiple other metrics.
- ightharpoonup Worked on bug fixes , new feature feasibility analysis and development , with primary focus on Linux and Solaris platform

Jan 2008 - Oct 2009 Pune , India Associate Projects, Cognizant Technology Solutions

$\begin{array}{l} \textbf{Languages} \ / \ \textbf{Technologies} \\ C/C++, Perl \end{array}$

- ▷ Developed applications and tools for the Credis Suisse US Equities booking team.
- ▷ EOD B2B trade processors and real-time data migration tool.
- $\, \rhd \,$ Developed Report generators , Worked on various bug fixes and code reviews.

May 2006 - Jan. 2008 Pune , India Senior Software Engineer, Symphony Services

LANGUAGES/TECHNOLOGIESC, Perl, Shell, Linux

- ▶ Worked as part of the platform team for the development of the Kazeon search appliance
- ▷ Back porting Kazeon specific kernel changes.
- > Ported the CCISS driver from 2.6 to 2.4 kernel. Worked on Broadcom Network card driver issues. Some of the required ETHTOOL ioctl's were not supported in the driver code. Made changes in the card driver code to support ethtool use.
- Developed a system configuration interactive Perl script to configure the Kazeon Appliance. The script configures the Hostname, IP Addresses, DNS, routes and static routes etc. Worked on Bug Fixes for various components in the Kazeon software.

March . 2005 - May. 2006 Pune , India Member of Technical Staff, Persistent Systems Pvt. Ltd.

LANGUAGES/TECHNOLOGIES C,PERL,SHELL,LINUX

- ▷ Applied Identity Project : Porting Windows application to Mac OS X. Project involved porting the GUI from Windows to Mac , porting the service to Mac.
- ▶ Mirapoint Project: Changed cpio and tar source code to add support for long file path handling capabilities. Made changes in cpio code to remove this limitation. Worked on Bug fixes for some components in Mirapoint code. Reiser 4 file system evaluation. Created system feasibility report for this file system to be used for client appliance. Calculated statistical result in text as well as graphical formats to represent the file system statistics. Comparing the results with ext3 and UFS as control values.

Dec 2003 - Dec 2004. Pune , India Member of Technical Staff, Calsoft Private Limited

LANGUAGES/TECHNOLOGIESC, TCL, FREEBSD

- Developed TCL based dynamic loadable modules in C for interacting with PANASAS NAS server. Work involved programming in C and TCL. The target NAS Server operating system is based on the FreeBSD. Wrote a Framework for Firing the NFS RPC using the TCL interpreter and the Application framework.
- ▷ Developed a remote network configuration using the Interface for configuring the NAS server.

4/5

Abhijeet Sane

Education

2002 - 2004 Master in Computer Applications, IGNOU

Pune,India Grades: 63.67%

1996 - 1999 Bachelor in Science (Chemistry), University Of Pune

Pune,India Grades: 58%

1996 H.S.C, Maharashtra Board

Pune,India Grades: 75%

1994 S.S.C, Maharashtra Board

Pune,India Grades: 80%

Abhijeet Sane 5/5